<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | Is This Code?]]></title>
  <link href="http://j-katz.net/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://j-katz.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-05T20:30:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://j-katz.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jacob Katzen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll, Octopress, and Github Page Hosting]]></title>
    <link href="http://j-katz.net/blog/2013/10/05/jekyll-octopress-github-pages/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-05T13:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://j-katz.net/blog/2013/10/05/jekyll-octopress-github-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><b>Hello World!</b></h3>


<p>Today I decided to take on the task of learning a thing or two about Jekyll, Octopress, and taking advantage of github pages to open a new blog that I've taken the liberty title 'Is this code?'</p>


<p>To be honest, initial setup took me a little longer than I had originally anticipated because of my lack of experience doing anything with ruby and rbenv.  For a little while, even though I had installed ruby1.9.3p448, I was still using my system's ruby1.8.7. The rbenv versions command helped me identify which version I could quickly enable with the rbenv local command.
``` sh
$ rbenv versions
$ rbenv local [version]
```
</p>


<p>After that was squared away, I was off to the races. I found a nice theme which I have applied and left unmodified for now after taking a look at this <a href="http://j-katz.net//github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-Party-Octopress-Themes">list</a>. I changed the font, because I didn't want to lay any money down for the typekit font this theme was loading, so I opted for <a href="http://j-katz.net//www.google.com/fonts">Google Web Fonts</a> because they are free and have a great selection. It also helps that Octopress has great integration with them already, which is all well-documented on their site <a href="http://j-katz.net//octopress.org/docs/theme/template/">here</a>. Basic configuration setup followed, along with some link changing and voilà, you get what you see here now.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
